# FATEMEH (SABA) MARZOUGHI (she/her)

### Software Developer

#### **Personal Info:**

- github.com/fatemehmarzoughi
- in/sabamarzoughi
- Iran-Tehran
- (98)919-5062977
- saba.marzoughi18@gmail.com

#### **About Me:**

I'm a software developer with 3 years of full-time experience in frontend development, alongside 2 years of part-time learning and practice in this field. During this professional journey, I have gained valuable experience developing diverse projects, improving my skills in JavaScript programming language and development tools. In the spare time, I concentrate on selfimprovement and develop personal projects. I'm excited for my next challenge where I can develop and implement mobile/web applications and be a part of a strong software engineering team.

#### Skills:

- Programming Languages
  - JavaScript, TypeScript
- Front-end technologies
  - HTML5, CSS3, SASS
  - React
- Design
  - OOP, FP
- Cross Platform Apps:
  - React-Native (Android, iOS)
  - Electron (Windows, MacOS)
- State Managements
  - Redux, Context
- ALM
  - GitOps
  - Postman
  - Jira, Trello, Figma
- CMS
  - Starpi
  - WordPress
- DB solutions
  - Realm
- API paradigms
  - REST, GraphQL

#### **Education:**

Sep 2017 - Dec 2021

 Bachelor of Computer Engineering (Software)

## **Professional Experiences:**

Front-end developer at UniPlato:

Australia (Remote),

The recommendation letter

Aug 2022 – May 2023

**Uniplato** is a team consisting of more than 15 members developing the "Coffee" platform, a meeting platform for scheduling and managing meetings with individuals or groups of people.

Visit Proiect

- Upgraded the "Coffee" platform by refactoring the old code structures of 2 old modules and bringing the modules back to the project.
- Enhanced platform stability by conducting more than 5 code reviews for new team members.
- Strengthened the codebase by developing over 15 pixel-perfect, responsive and well-structured **React** components, making the components accessible to all team members across all the modules as part of the project design system.
- Delivered over 10 new features, complete with demos, to the platform through collaborative communication with team members and the adept utilization of REST API and web sockets.
- Directed the Mac desktop app functionalities, prioritising features and managing development to align with user needs and business objectives.
- Collaborated with the new/junior team members to tackle challenges and overcome obstacles besides working independence in each task.

Front-end developer at Comfortel:

The recommendation letter

Russia (Remote),

Visit Project

Dec 2021 - May 2022

**Comfortel** is an Internet service provider company the team consists of over 15 members developing the "**Techpal**" project which consists of different platforms: Inkpal, Chatpal, and Gitpal.

- Elevated team communication by implementing customization across the Mattermost platform, ensuring a seamless experience on desktop (Windows and Mac) using **Electron** and mobile on Android operating system.
- Enhanced the usability of the "**Techpal**" platform by launching the desktop application on three different operating systems (Windows, mac, and Linux) with Electron, while also developing the Android application using **React-Native**.
- Documented the codes, ensuring that provides clear explanations for other developers to easily comprehend different sections of the codebase.

Front-end developer (Freelancing and Open-source):

Tehran, <u>Visit Project</u> Nov 2020 – Dec 2021

**MyPlayer** is an open-source React Native project, serving as an audio/video provider platform. This platform utilizes Strapi as the content management system and also the app is accessible on both iOS and Android operating systems.

- Transitioned from class-base structures to functional ones, to harness the power of hooks. This transformation let to a remarkable performance enhancement particularly noticeable on older Android devices.
- Refactored old code structure that resulted in removing 3 useless and extra packages from the project and reduced the bundle size.

Front-end developer at Bytino:

ehran, Visit Project Nov 2019 – Nov 2020

**Bytino** is a startup team comprising frontend, backend, and designer members with the primary mission being the creation of outstanding web pages.

- Improved team's portfolio resulting in the acquisition of 2 new projects by creating one-page websites that showcased the team capability.
- Created 2 web pages templates that have the potential to expedite project implementation.
- Enhancing businesses customers by 10% with developing webpages using WordPress.